Briana Breaux

Software Engineer

Birmingham, AL (904) 508–4652 bri LinkedIn GitHub Portfolio

brianabreaux@gmail.com

Professional Summary

Highly skilled professional with exceptional soft skills and over 10 years of experience in leadership in the cosmetology industry. Focusing on Full-Stack development, I've built strong technical skills in server building, database management, and API construction using Python, as well as NodeJS and Express. Using Front-End frameworks such as React and MaterialUI, I build beautiful and intuitive user-focused web applications.

Technical Skills

HTML & CSS, JavaScript, Python, SQL, PostgreSQL, SQLAlchemy, Flask, NodeJS, Express, ReactJS, DOM Manipulation and Event-Driven Programming, Git/Github, Object-Oriented Programming(OOP), Test Driven Development, Testing with Jasmine and Jest, AJAX & jQuery, Data Structures and Algorithms, RESTful APIs, Software Development Life Cycle

Software Engineering Projects

Capstone I - Moment of Clarity

Moment of Clarity offers people in sobriety a guide to alcohol-free mocktails. Moment of Clarity was built with Python, using Flask as the framework, and PostgreSQL as the database. Flask-SQLAlchemy was chosen as the ORM, Flask-WTForms to authenticate forms in the application, and Flask-Bcrypt to authorize and authenticate user information. Data was taken and cleaned from TheCocktailDB.

Capstone II - Book Friend

Book Friend offers users the opportunity to search their favorite author's information as well as a comprehensive list of all of the author's works. The back-end side of Book Friend was built using Express and Node, utilizing jsonchema to validate JSON documents, and jsonwebtoken and bcrypt to authorize and authenticate users. The front-end side was built using React and Bootstrap 4. PostgreSQL was chosen as the database, and testing was done using Jest and React Testing Library.

Education

Springboard Software Engineering Career Track - Certification

MAY 2021 - FEBRUARY 2022.

9-month intensive course in Software Engineering methodologies and technologies, with 1:1 industry expert mentor oversight, and completion of 2 in-depth portfolio projects. Mastered skills in full-stack development, databases, and data structures and algorithms.

Work Experience

Sport Clips, Great Clips, Orange Park, FL — Assistant Manager/Stylist

MARCH 2011 - MAY 2016. MAY 2016 - DECEMBER 2019

 Efficiently Delegated Tasks to a Team of 13 people, Increased Customer Engagement with Specialized Marketing Strategy, Meticulously Maintained Business Paperwork, Formulated an Improved Inventory Management System, and Fostered Employee Growth by Implementing an Accountability and Encouragement System